[Respect Copyright, Everyone's Responsibility]
[저작권 보호는 모두의 책임입니다]
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설 '천향인' 각색 작품]
[Episode 2]
[제2화]
Who's there?
누구냐!
It's you...
너였어?
You followed me again!
또 나를 미행했어?
Followed you?
내가 너를 미행했다고?
I have no money for an inn, so I can only stay here.
숙박할 돈이 없어서 여기서 묵을 수밖에 없었다
I was here first anyway.
게다가 내가 먼저 온 것 같은데
When did you get here? What did you hear?
언제 왔고 무엇을 들었느냐?
I slept
난 방금 잠들었다
until the aroma of roast chicken woke me.
구운 닭 냄새에 깼을 뿐이다
Sir,
저기
have we met somewhere before?
우리 만난 적이 있지 않소?
I'm Lei Xiuyuan, an exam applicant.
서원 시험 보러 온 뇌수원이라 하오
I think we've never met.
형씨와는 처음 뵙는 사이인 것 같소
We're here for the exam too.
우리도 서원 시험 보러 왔소
Fate brought us together. Let's journey together
만난 것은 인연이니 함께 동행하는 것이 좋을 듯하오
and look out for each other.
서로 의지할 수도 있을 테니
- Great idea... - No way!
- 좋소 - 안 좋습니다
Who are you? What's your motive?
너는 누구고 무슨 목적이냐?
Speak properly, Xiaobangchui.
소방추, 말을 예쁘게 하십시오
Quiet!
입 다무십시오
First your brother, then the academy exam.
형님 찾는다더니 이제 와서 서원 시험 보러 왔다고?
As if I'd believe you. Speak!
그 말을 믿을 리 없다, 솔직히 대거라
Chufeng Academy is the safest place in the world.
추봉서원은 천하에서 가장 안전한 곳이다
It remains neutral through immortal feuds
선문 간 충돌이든 범계 전란이든
and mortal wars alike.
절대 중립을 지킨다
My brother is in danger.
지금 형님이 위태로우니
Only by getting into the academy can I save him.
서원에 입학해야만 형님을 구할 수 있다
You said your master's lost.
너는 스승님을 잃었다며
Why take the academy exam suddenly?
서원 시험은 왜서 보는 거냐?
I…?
나?
I need to improve my skills to find my master.
실력을 키워야 스승님을 찾을 수 있지
Me too.
나도 마찬가지다
Only strength
강해져야
can protect the ones I love.
주변 사람들을 지킬 수 있다
Why keep staring at me?
왜 나를 쳐다보는 것이오?
I'm not that tomboy.
내가 저 남자 같은 여자도 아니고
Xigu Village lies in Gaolu.
계곡촌은 고로에 위치하고
Since you're from Gaolu,
형씨는 고로 사람이니
do you know Mr. Lei, the military commander?
병권을 쥔 뇌 대인을 아시는가?
Gaolu is long gone.
고로는 진작에 사라졌소
I have no country, no home left.
나는 나라도 집도 없는 사람일 뿐이오
No country, no home…
나라도 집도 없다니
I'm just like you,
나도 마찬가지로
homeless and stateless.
나라도 집도 없는 사람이오
Your clothes are torn. My sister can sew.
옷이 찢어졌소, 우리 여동생이 바느질에 능하니
Let her mend them for you.
수선하게 하시오
No need.
됐소
We have trials tomorrow. Better look decent.
내일 시련이 있으니 단정하게 입어야 하오
Your Highness.
태자 전하
[Young Ye Ye]
[어린 시절 엽엽] 얼른 옷을 벗어 주십시오
Yuan, Mr. Lei died defending our realm.
원아, 뇌 대인은 이미 나라를 지키기 위해 목숨을 잃으셨다
As his adopted son,
너는 그의 의자식이니
you must safeguard His Highness like him.
마땅히 그를 대신해 전하를 지켜야 한다
Do you understand?
알겠느냐?
Are you truly unfamiliar with Mr. Lei?
정말 뇌 대인을 모르는가?
I'll say this one last time: I do not know him.
마지막으로 답하는데 모르오
Forget the torn clothes.
옷이 찢어진 게 뭐가 대수라고
Hurry undress and get some sleep.
얼른 벗고 잠이나 자
Don't you remember why we came to Lugong Town?
육공진에 왜 왔는지 잊었어?
My apologies.
미안하오
I must've missed my old friend so much
고인이 너무 그리워서
that I mistook you for him.
잘못 봤소
[Lugong Town] The spirit root test begins.
[육공진] 영측을 시작한다
Fire Spirit Root. Pass.
화영근, 합격
You're amazing!
오라버니, 정말 대단하시네요
You'll definitely rank first.
분명 일등일 겁니다
What's a single Fire Spirit Root?
단일 화영근이 무엇입니까?
Spirit roots correspond to the Five Elements: Metal, Wood, Water, Fire, Earth.
영근은 오행 금목수화토로 나뉘고
Most folks have mixed spirit roots,
대부분 사람들의 영근은 잡다하여
two or three kinds combined.
두 개 혹은 세 개의 영근을 갖습니다
Only those with extraordinary talent
오직 천부가 뛰어난 자만이
possess a single spirit root.
단일 영근을 갖고 있지요
Anyone with a single spirit root
그리고 단일 영근을 가진 이들은
is a rare cultivation prodigy.
수련의 천재라 불립니다
Single Wood Spirit Root.
단일 목영근이군
Let's go.
가서 보죠
Excuse me.
비켜 주십시오
Illusion talisman cheating!
영부로 부정행위를 저질러?
Kick him out and blacklist him for life.
쫓아내고 다시는 받지 않는다
Top Metal Spirit Root.
최상급 금영근이군
Metal Spirit Root.
금영근
Pass.
합격이다
Wait a minute.
잠깐만
Could it be another illusion talisman trick?
또 환영부인 건 아니겠지?
Lei Yuan, it's really you.
뇌원, 정말 너였구나
All those born with a Metal Spirit Root
자고로 금영근을 가진 자들은
are destined for extraordinary immortal cultivation.
반드시 선도를 이루니
Come study under me.
내 문하로 들어오면
I will pass down all my knowledge without reserve.
내가 가진 것을 전부 전수해 주겠다
No need.
됐습니다
What's a Metal Spirit Root?
오라버니, 금영근이 무엇인가요?
I don't think he can be better than you.
그가 어찌 오라버니보다 더 대단하겠어요?
That old man must be senile.
저 노인네가 정신이 나간 게 틀림없어요
There is always someone stronger.
뛰는 놈 위에 나는 놈이 있는 법
We should treat gifted folks with courtesy
정말 재능 있다면 예를 갖추고
and recruit them early.
일찍 친해지는 게 좋다
Your Metal Spirit Root sounds so powerful.
금영근이 엄청 대단한 모양인데
Lend me some of it.
조금만 빌려줘봐
Spirit roots cannot be lent to others.
영근을 빌릴 수 있는 게 아닙니다
I…
저...
- Your turn. - I…
- 부르고 있습니다 - 저요?
She's calling you.
그쪽을 부르는 겁니다
No spirit root detected.
영근이 없네
Please check again.
선생님, 한 번만 다시
Check more closely.
자세히 살펴주십시오
She truly has no spirit root at all.
오라버지, 그녀 역시 영근이 없었네요
Maybe my spirit root is hiding somewhere!
어딘가 숨은 거 아닐까요?
Please.
다시
Check again.
봐주세요
Xiaobangchui, hold your breath!
소봉추야, 얼른 숨을 참아라
W-What's that?
저건 뭐지?
Dual weak spirit roots with Wood primary, and Earth secondary.
약한 쌍영근, 주목 부토다
Pass.
합격
Thanks.
감사합니다
Your meridians are sealed. No spirit roots can be detected.
맥력이 봉인되었으니 영근을 알아볼 수 없었을 뿐
Passed.
합격했네요
Clearly, it's a fox spirit's doing.
분명 여우요괴가 장난을 친 것이다
Riyan lives inside her.
일염은 그녀 몸 안에 있어
Lei.
형씨
What's up?
무슨 일인가?
Metal Spirit Roots are incredibly rare.
금영근은 정말 보기 드무니
May I see yours again?
다시 한번 구경하게 해줄 수 있소?
No time.
시간 없소
Wait!
잠깐만
We can team up
형씨, 내일 시련이 있으니
for tomorrow's trial
우릭 서로 협력해
to get into the academy faster.
빨리 서원에 들어가는 게 어떻소?
I don't care about the academy.
나는 서원에 관심 없소
Then why sit the exam?
관심 없으면서 왜 시험 보러 왔소?
Who exactly are you?
대체 정체가 무엇이오?
Spirit or ghost,
네가 요괴든 뭐든
come out now!
빨리 나와
Or
아니면
I'll shave all my hair off,
머리를 다 밀어버려
so you'll have nowhere to hide.
어디로 도망가나 보자
Wait.
나...
Are you really a girl?
너 계집애가 맞긴 해?
You'd sacrifice your own hair.
자기 머리카락까지 자를 줄이야
You're that Qingqiu fox.
너 청구에 있던 그 여우구나
[Riyan, Nine-Tailed Fox]
[구미호 일염] 나는 천 년을 수련한 구미호
My name is Riyan.
일염이라 한다
Ri as in sunlight,
해와 함께 빛날 일
Yan as in blazing flame.
활활 타오를 염
Riyan.
일염이라고
A thousand years of cultivation? Sounds powerful.
천 년이나 수련했으면 엄청 대단한 거 아니냐?
Why'd you hide inside me?
왜 내 몸에 숨어 지내는 것이야?
Only because your ma...
네 그 사...
I mean, you're such an unlucky fool.
네가 불운한 놈이니까 도와주는 거다
I'm willing to aid you. Show some gratitude!
얼른 고마워하지 않겠나?
Come on! They were chasing you,
됐거든, 분명 그 사람들이 널 쫓아다니니까
and you hid on my head!
내 머리 위에 숨은 거잖아
Wait!
아니
You saw everything when I went
그럼 내가 뒷간에 가고 목욕할 때
to the latrine and bathed!
다 보았다는 거야?
My spirit body's injured, and all my senses shut down.
나는 영체가 손상되었고 육감을 모두 닫혔다
Besides,
그리고
what's there to see anyway?
볼 게 무엇이 있겠는가?
Your spirit body's hurt? Is it that bad?
영체가 손상되었다니 엄청 심각한 일이잖아
It's nothing much.
그럭저럭
Might take three to five years to heal fully.
삼오년은 수양해야 할 듯하다
Three to five years? That's ages!
삼오년이라고? 그렇게 오래?
Will you pay rent for hiding here?
그럼 집세는 낼 것이냐?
Ignorant girl!
견식도 짧은 계집애로군
I've condescended
내가 몸을 낮추고
to rest in your hair.
네 머리카락 속에서 쉬는 건
This is an honor for you!
네 영광이다
Old spirit,
천 년 묵은 요괴 주제에
you've grown shameless with age!
갈수록 뻔뻔해지는군
So it's you.
너였구나
How many lovers have you ruined for centuries?
수백 년 동안 얼마나 많은 남녀를 괴롭혔느냐?
What do you mean?
괴롭히다니
[Little Matchmaker] I match people up and build goodwill.
[소월로] 나는 선의로 인연을 맺어줄 뿐이다
You two know each other?
너희 둘 아는 사이야?
When you live long enough,
오래 살다 보니
you're bound to meet shady folks.
잡다한 요괴를 알 수도 있지
Right, stinky fox?
그치, 여우야
He is here.
그 자식이 왔네
Xiaobangchui,
소봉추
who are you talking to?
누구랑 얘기하고 있었어?
No one at all!
아니야, 아무것도
Come, I need to talk to you.
가자, 할 얘기가 있다
Really?
그래?
[Lugong Town]
[육공진]
[Yange Hall]
[연가방]
Thanks.
감사합니다
Don't just stare.
보고만 있지 말고
Here,
자
have some meat.
고기 먹어봐
Trying to test me?
날 시험하려고?
Here. Drink some water to cut the grease.
자, 물 좀 마셔
Drink with me.
같이 마시자
Still plotting against me.
또 나를 속이려고?
The truth-telling spell doesn't work.
진술주가 통하지 않는군
You poisoned the water too.
물에도 독을 탔어?
Your head's spinning, right?
지금 머리가 어지럽지?
You took my soul-bewitching powder,
방금 내 미혼산을 마셨으니
so your head is buzzing,
머리가 윙윙거리고
and your tongue won't cooperate, huh?
혀가 말을 듣지 않지?
Yeah.
그래
Good. Tell me.
잘됐다, 말해봐라
Why are you getting close to me?
왜 나한테 접근한 것이냐?
Stop struggling. Tell the truth.
저항하지 말고 말해
After my money?
내 재물을 탐내는 것이냐
Or my master?
아니면 우리 사부님을 노리는 것이냐?
Who's your master?
네 사부님이 누군데?
Not after my master.
사부님을 노리는 게 아니라고
Then what?
그럼 뭔데?
I... I need to survive
살아남아서
to save my brother.
형님을 살리기 위해서다
Save your brother? None of my business.
형님을 살리는 게 나랑 뭔 상관인데?
Won't talk, huh?
안 말할 거냐?
Then meet your end.
그럼 죽어
Excuse me,
두 분
pay the bill before fighting, and take it outside.
계산부터 하고 밖에 나가서 싸우세요
Otherwise, you can't afford
아니면 이 찻잔과 주전가 값을
to break all these teapots and cups.
배상하기 어려울 겁니다
Thirty liang for this tea?
뭔 차가 30냥입니까?
You're robbing us!
돈을 뜯어내는 거 아닙니까?
Can we... put it on credit?
저기, 외상 가능한가요?
Sorry, no credit here.
죄송한데 외상은 받지 않습니다
[Mr. Yan, Owner of Yange Hall]
[연 방주]
He's a natural opera performer!
노래를 잘하게 생겼군
Truly outstanding.
괜찮네
And he's got quite a temper.
성질이 강하군
I like that.
마음에 드네
Mr. Yan. If you like him,
방주, 마음에 드시면
I'll sell him to you. Interested?
제가 팔게요
He masters both literary and martial arts,
문무를 겸비했으니
the finest talent in Lugong Town.
육공진에서 찾기 힘든 인재입니다
The price is merely a meal,
한 끼 식사와
plus leaked trial questions. What a bargain!
시련 문제까지 더하죠
Why hasn't Xiuyuan come back yet?
수원은 왜 아직 돌아오지 않는 거지?
He has a single spirit root.
뇌 형씨는 단일 영근이니
Some mentor might have recruited him
어느 선생께 직접 거두어 갔을지도
on the spot.
모르잖아요
You'd better worry about yourself.
일단 본인 걱정부터 하십시오
This trial is said to be tougher than the previous ones.
이번 시련이 전보다 훨씬 어렵다던데
By rough reckoning,
대략 계산해 보니
less than ten percent will pass.
통과할 수 있는 자는 일 할도 되지 않아요
Even I fell for such a low trick.
정말 사기를 당했네
Look, these exam questions are five years old.
이건 오 년 전의 시험 문제잖아, 보세요
I told you they were unreliable.
믿을 수 없을 줄 알았어요
Yange Hall has stood in Lugong Town for centuries,
연가방은 육공진에서 수백 년 자리 잡았거늘
yet nobody knows Mr. Yan's true background.
아직도 방주의 정체는 아무도 모른대요
How dare you buy exam questions from him?
그가 파는 문제도 사다니
What a crafty old thing.
참 교활하지 그지없군
I need to bring up a big shot
모든 문제를 내놓게 하려면
to make him give out all the questions.
큰 인물을 데려와야겠네
Just some gifts, please accept them.
작은 성의니 방주께서 받아주십시오
These are predicted two-choice test questions sorted
이건 왕년 경험으로
from past records.
추측한 두 번째 문제들입니다
Your Highness, here you are.
잘 간수하십시오
I'll open this for you.
제가 열어드리겠습니다
No...
아니
This is way too much!
양이 너무 많은 거 아닙니까?
It covers astrology, divination
점성, 점술, 기문둔갑
and cultivation arts from every school.
각 공파의 수법을 두루 섭렵했습니다
If you master all of this,
이 모든 것을 연마한다면
I'm sure you'll pass the trials.
합격을 장담하지요
This isn't just food.
이게 음식이 아니라
It's pure silver! Such extravagance.
그저 은자들잖아요, 너무 사치스럽습니다
This suits me perfectly.
정말 제 취향에 맞네요
Where's Lei Xiuyuan?
뇌수원은요?
Why isn't he with you?
왜 보이지 않는 겁니까?
He...
걔는
he is staying right where
당연히 있어야 할 곳에
he ought to be.
있겠지요
Flower Fairy, where are you?
화선, 어디에 있느냐?
[Miaoqing]
[묘청]
Flower Fairy? Demon Lord?
화선, 마군
Records of Immortals and Demons in the Sea of Illusory Love?
'정천환해신마록'이네
Save me!
살려줘
Xiaobangchui!
소봉추
Get me out of here!
나 살려줘
This place is pretty nice.
여기가 얼마나 좋아?
Stay here, or you'll bring me troubles.
그냥 여기에 있어, 날 해칠 생각 말고
If you don't save me, I'll never let go.
날 살려주지 않으면 이 손 놓지 않을 거다
You!
너...
Let go of me!
이거 놔
Your Highness.
소왕야, 소왕야
Help me!
살려주십시오
Please! Your Highness!
왕야, 살려주십시오
Leave her be.
신경 쓰지 마세요
Let go!
이거 놔
Watch out!
조심
These assassins can't see a thing.
멍청한 살수들, 눈이 하나같이 어둡군
Your Highness, run!
왕야, 도망가십시오
They've come to kill you!
왕야를 죽이러 온 겁니다
Stop them!
저들을 막아
Let me go!
이거 놔라
Who dares stir up trouble here?
누가 감히 연가방에서 소란을 피우냐?
Where are they?
어딜 갔지?
Thank you for saving us
왕야께서 위기를 막아내고
and chasing the killers away.
자객들을 물치셔서 다행입니다
You said
소봉추
they were targeting me.
방금 저자들이 저를 노리고 왔다고요?
It doesn't matter who they targeted.
그건 상관없습니다
All thanks to Your Highness,
왕야께서 복이 넘치시고
sheltered by heaven,
하늘의 비호가 있으니
we've all got a share of your fortune
다들 그 복을 나눠
and made it out safe.
화를 면하게 되었죠
Is Lei Xiuyuan the one you are looking for?
뇌수원이 정말 오라버니가 찾던 사람이라고요?
Yes.
맞다
He's got the Gaolu clan mark.
그의 몸에 우리 고로 족인이 새겨져 있었다
Gaolu was destroyed long ago, and our whole clan was killed.
옛날 고로가 함락되어 전족이 몰살되었고
To let me escape,
어머님께서 내가 살아남게 하려고
my mom sent Lei Yuan, Mr. Lei's adopted kid,
뇌 대인의 의자식인 뇌원이
to pretend to be me
내 신분을 대신하게 하여
and lead Wugou's and the Longming Sanctuary's killers away.
오구와 용명좌의 추살을 분산시켰다
He was only eleven,
그때 그는 겨우 열한 살이었고
six months younger than me.
나보다도 반 살 어렸었다
Only Mr. Lu was with him.
노 시위만 그를 따라갔어서
We all thought he died.
우린 그가 죽은 줄 알았는데
Turns out
아직
he's alive.
살아 있었군
Get lost.
죽을 거면 멀리 가서 죽어
I want to survive
난 살아 남아서
and find my brother.
형님을 찾아내야 한다
So pitiful.
정말 가엾군
But none of my business.
하지만 나랑 무슨 상관이지?
What? Save Lei Xiuyuan?
뇌수원을 구하겠다고요?
Who said she'd obey every word
방금 누가 저를 위해 앞장서고
I say?
지시대로 따르겠다 하였죠?
I don't mean to refuse,
아니, 싫은 게 아니라
but this guy
뇌수원은
is unlucky, and I fear it will taint your luck.
타고난 액운을 지녀 왕야의 운수에 영향이 갈까 봐요
Nonsense!
됐거든요
Tongzhou's luck
저희 오라버니 같은 천운을
won't be ruined by some wild guy.
그런 놈 따위가 어찌 흔들 수 있겠습니까?
No. He's a walking bad luck magnet.
아니, 그 사람의 액운은 타고났다니깐요
Think about it.
생각해 보세요
He alone brought death to his entire village,
혼자서 온 마을 사람들을 모두 죽게 하고
and even crossed the Longming Sanctuary.
용명좌까지 건드리고
How ill-omened that is!
얼마나 불길해요
No need to worry about that.
그건 신경 쓰지 마십시오
Just get him out,
그를 꺼내주기면 하면
and I'll let you join the trial with me.
제가 시련에 함께 가겠습니다
Do I have to go rescue him?
구하는 일은 제가 가지 않아도 되잖아요
Can't we just bribe Mr. Yan?
방주한테 돈 좀 주면 되지 않나요?
You think I haven't thought of that?
그건 저도 압니다
I tried bribing him ages ago,
전에 돈을 주려 했으나
but he wouldn't accept
그 방주가 고집만 부리고
whatever I offered.
받지 않겠다잖아요
If even you can't sway him,
군주마저 방도가 없다면
I stand no chance at all.
저야 더욱 힘들겠죠
[Yue Law] The Yue Law states clearly:
[월율] 월국 율법에 분명히 적혀 있네요
Human traffickers get 300 cane blows, and two years of hard labor.
인신매매는 곤장 삼백 대에 징역 이 년이고
Lugong Town is part of the Yue State, so…
- 육공진도 월국에 속하니 - 저기
Since Your Highness wants him,
왕야께서 원하시는 사람이라면
I'll bring him back safe and sound.
제가 반드시 모셔다 드려야지요
Hold your needle!
잠깐만요
Sir! Sir!
방주님, 방주님
Oh, no.
저기
Even if he is being stubborn,
방주님, 이 애가 말을 안 들으면
you can discipline him,
혼내면 되지
but he doesn't deserve death.
죽일 필요까지는 없잖아요
There is a Longming Sanctuary's toxic mark on his nape.
이자 목 뒤에 용명좌의 독인이 새겨져서
I meant to cure him with the golden needle.
금침으로 해독하려 했는데
But you burst in,
와서 방해하는 바람에
and the needle struck the Fengchi acupoint.
풍지혈을 찌르고 말았네요
Now he's paralyzed in the face.
이것 봐, 안면 마비가 왔네
He can't speak properly today.
오늘도 말하기 힘들 것 같군요
It's all a misunderstanding.
오해했네요, 방주님
Misunderstanding?
오해라고요?
You may use the front door,
정문으로 들어오지 않고
yet flew in through the window.
굳이 창문으로 날아들어오다니
To tell you the truth,
솔직히
I came here specially to visit you.
저는 방주님 뵈러 왔습니다
Oh? Want to sell yourself to my hall too?
왜, 당신도 연가방에서 일하려고요?
About the unfinished opera from yesterday,
어제 끝내지 못한 극의
I came to ask how it ends.
결말을 여쭤보려고요
You know Records of Immortals and Demons in the Sea of Illusory Love?
당신도 '정천환해선마록'을 아십니까?
Sure, I've read over twenty versions.
그럼요, 스무여 가지 판본을 봤었습니다
Which version do you like best?
어떤 판본이 가장 마음에 들었습니까?
The one marked Yan.
연자호 그 판이요
It states the Flower Fairy giggles, turns around,
거기에 화선이 웃으며 돌아서서
lifts her skirt,
치마폭을 들고
and kicks the Demon Lord straight off the Immortal Execution Platform.
마군을 발로 주선대에서 차버렸잖아요
So satisfying, utterly stirring!
얼마나 속 시원하고 감동적인지
A kindred spirit!
동지로군요
Let's talk inside.
안으로 들어와 얘기하지요
Alright.
예
Make tea for our guest.
가서 손님께 차를 내와라
Don't sit there like a log!
나무토막처럼 앉아있지 말고
Brew the finest tea.
좋은 차로 내와
This way, please.
자, 이리 오십시오
Why not stay here and partner up with me?
아니면 이곳에 남아서 협력하지요
Let me tell you, with great stories in hand,
좋은 이야기만 있으면
we can dominate all realms.
천하를 자유롭게 다닐 수 있습니다
Sounds great!
좋지요
But I have to take the academy exam
하지만 먼저 서원 시험을 보고
and find my family.
가족을 찾아야 해서
You…
그럼...
What's wrong with you? So clumsy!
어떻게 된 거냐?
Can't even serve tea properly.
차도 제대로 들지 못해?
What? Want to beat me?
뭐야, 손까지 대려고?
Look.
이것 보세요
Mr. Yan,
방주님
I run my business
저는 장사꾼으로
by one rule:
물건 좋고
top quality, fair prices, honest to both young and old.
가격도 공평해야 하거든요
He is far from qualified.
이 상품은 아직이니
Look. I'll take him back to train properly
제가 데려가 훈육한 뒤
and bring him back to you, alright?
다시 가져다 드릴게요
Let's go.
가자
Don't bother over such trivial matters.
이런 일로 수고하실 필요는 없습니다
I'll train him myself.
제가 직접 훈육하면 됩니다
Think about it.
방주님, 보십시오
You're swamped with work and still writing stories
온갖 일도 처리하시고 책도 써서
for us fans.
저 같은 독자들을 생각하니
How could I let you waste time on this?
이런 일로 수고하실 수 없죠
I'm taking him away now. Come on.
제가 먼저 데려가겠습니다, 가자
Stop.
잠깐
Xiaobangchui, that's not fair play.
소방추, 이건 도리가 아니지요
I bought him with my money.
사람은 제가 돈 주고 산 건데
You can't just take him away as you please.
마음대로 데려가다니
I'll pay you back the food cost.
식사 값은 돌려드릴게요
No need.
됐습니다
Rare goods once sold, no refunds.
귀한 물건은 다시 돌려줄 수 없는 법
I'm taking him away no matter what.
이 사람은 꼭 데려가야겠습니다
Go!
가자
You can't take him away.
데려갈 수 없습니다
You're not going anywhere today.
오늘 아무도 여기서 나가지 못해
You!
너...
Run!
얼른 가자
I'm returning him unharmed.
안전하게 데려왔습니다
The trial's starting. Get over there.
시련이 시작하니 빨리 가지요
You helped me?
당신이 도와준 거요?
No problem. Let's take the trial together.
고마워할 필요 없고 같이 시험 보러 가지요
That's great to have Your Highness with us.
왕야랑 같이 가니 정말 다행이네요
If you ever harm me again,
또 날 해치려 하면
I'll skin, dismember and sell you by weight.
네 가죽을 벗겨서 팔아버릴 거다
Your Highness has magic treasures,
왕야한테 법보가 있고
Lei Xiuyuan has spirit power,
뇌수원한테는 영력이 있고
and I've got wits.
저는 똑똑하니
We will be unbeatable.
저희 셋이면 무적이겠네요
Let's go now.
같이 시험 보러 가죠
Only by slaying the host can I force the fox spirit out.
숙주를 죽여야만 여우를 꺼낼 수 있다
Move.
가자
It's time.
시간이 다 되었다
You have 24 hours from now.
지금부터 열두 시진 동안
Make it out of this valley
내일 오시 전까지
before noon tomorrow,
이 산곡에서 빠져나가면
and you'll pass the second trial.
2차 시련에 합격하는 것이다
The trial begins.
시련 시작
What are you doing here? Get away!
당신은 왜 왔습니까? 비켜요
Let's go.
갑시다
Your Highness!
왕야
Anyone here?
누구 없어요?
Tongzhou, are you still mad at me?
오라버니, 아직도 화나 있어요?
Tongzhou,
오라버니
Xiaobangchui
소봉추는
isn't on our side at all.
저희랑 길이 다르잖아요
I was afraid she'd slow us down.
저희 발목 잡을까 봐 그래요
Still, you shouldn't be so reckless.
그래도 막 행동하면 안 되지
If you do this again,
다음에 또 이러면
I'll send you back.
널 돌려보낼 거다
Alright. I won't do it next time.
알겠어요, 다시는 안 그럴게요
Don't send me away.
절 돌려보내지 마세요
Anyone here? Make a sound!
누구 있으면 소리라도 내봐요
Oh, no. I lost my powerful ally.
이런, 의지할 사람도 잃었네
It's freezing cold.
너무 춥다
Why is it so frigid?
왜 이렇게 춥지?
We must get out of here soon,
빨리 이곳에서 빠져나가야 돼
or else…
아니면...
Bless me.
보우해 주소서
This will work.
이건 되겠네
The ancient Zhurong Stone.
상고 축융석
Xuanshanzi really splurged a fortune on this.
현산자 그 영감이 아끼지를 않는군
Tongzhou, you're amazing!
오라버니, 정말 대단해요
Let's go.
가자
Never thought someone so young
어린 나이에
could wield an ancient spirit treasure.
상고 영보를 다룰 수 있다니
Truly an extraordinary talent.
천부가 참 뛰어나군
He is using Xingzheng Hall's supreme treasure,
성정관의 진관 보물도 쓸 수 있으니
so he's got a huge edge over other examinees.
다른 시험생들보다 많이 유리하겠군
- Li, that's not right. - Stop arguing.
- 이 선배, 그건 편견이오 - 조용하시오
Let's check the others.
다른 이들도 살펴보시오
There may be someone stronger.
더욱 대단한 인물이 있을지도 모르니까
No way,
설마
not this again.
또 와?
♪I trade all the mortal world's splendor♪
♪세속의 화려함 모두 안고 와♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪잠시 너와 맞바꿨어♪
♪Our fates intertwined, embracing yet fighting♪
♪운명의 끈 얽혀 안고 서로 해치는 건♪
It's you.
너였어?
♪The hardest bond to balance♪
♪가장 어울리는 인연♪
Where's His Highness?
왕야는?
How should I know?
내가 어떻게 알겠어?
Stay alive. I'm retreating.
버티고 있어, 나 먼저 갈게
Bro... jump with me!
친구야, 같이 뛰어내리자
All limbs intact, thank heavens I had a cushion.
팔 다리 온전하네, 받쳐줄 사람이 있어 다행이군
Can't attack openly, or the academy will find out.
내놓고 해치면 서원에 들통날 거다
Lost your wits?
정신 나갔어?
It'd be easier if he really lost his wits.
정말 정신 잃었으면 오히려 편하지
Say something. Are you alright?
말 좀 해봐
Speak to me.
말 좀 해보라고
You're actually fine.
정신 차렸군
Are you
너...
cold?
추워?
Obviously, snow and ice are everywhere.
당연하지, 얼음 천지인데
Of course, I'm cold.
안 춥겠어?
What? Trying to trick me again?
왜 그래, 또 나 속이려고?
Don't move.
가만히 있어
Why's my whole body warming up?
온몸이 따뜻해졌네
You're channeling your spirit power to me?
지금 나에게 영력을 넣어주고 있어?
No wonder I took a fancy to you, Metal Spirit Root.
역시 내가 알아본 금영근답군
Putting others first, so kind and righteous.
남을 먼저 챙기는 마음과 덕이 있어
Those examinees are quite hopeful.
이번 시험생들도 희망이 있네
Two more trials left.
아직 두 관문이 남았습니다
If I kill her now,
이 기회에 그녀를 죽이면
the fox spirit may reveal itself to save her.
요호가 나타나 구해줄 것이다
Now's the chance to shatter her meridians.
지금 그녀 맥을 부숴야 한다
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설 '천향인' 각색 작품]
♪It's me, blinded by longing♪
♪내 눈에 병이 생긴 건지♪
♪Every glance lands on you♪
♪눈앞에 온통 너만 가득하네♪
♪Fire and water clash, yet we cling inseparably♪
♪물불은 어울릴 수 없는데 끈끈히 붙어있네♪
♪Lotus broken, threads still bind us♪
♪연은 끊어져도 실은 서로를 잇고♪
♪My heart calm till you stir storms and rain♪
♪내 마음 잔잔한테 넌 비를 내리게 하네♪
♪You are my destined rival♪
♪넌 나의 숙적♪
♪Winters pass, springs come; bound for lifetimes, fate ties me to you♪
♪봄이 오고 생사 함께할 운명은 너에게 달렸네♪
♪Mountains, rivers, lakes and seas, I follow no one but you♪
♪산과 바다를 가리지 않고 너만 따라가리♪
♪Bitterness brews sweet bliss, drained in one sip♪
♪쓴 아픔 속 달콤함을 빚어 마시고♪
♪Love and feud balance out, I'm yours alone♪
♪사랑과 원한을 상쇄하고 너를 마음에 새기네♪
♪Fated foes, fate plays tricks; you complete my five elements♪
♪숙명의 적인데 하늘이 맺어 오행에는 너만 빠졌네♪
♪Burning love, unbridled hatred, they suit each other well♪
♪사랑은 뜨겁고 미움은 시원하니 서로 어울리네♪
♪If you don't leave, I'll never abandon you♪
♪네가 떠나지 않는다면 나 또한 포기하지 않으리♪
♪We'll dwell in mortal dust, stay side by side till the end♪
♪이렇게 속세에서 끝까지 함께하리♪
♪Sometimes I throw petty fits♪
♪가끔 투정 부리지♪
♪I blame all troubles on you♪
♪모든 건 네 탓이라며♪
♪Though distant on the surface, our souls resonate as one♪
♪겉은 달라도 마음은 통하는데♪
♪We wander far, parted to separate corners♪
♪각자 먼 길 떠나도♪
♪Yet my heart still leans toward you, my foe♪
♪어쩔 수 없이 마음은 기울고♪
♪I sigh and laugh, defeated in this game of affection♪
♪또 패배한 판을 웃으면 바라보네♪
♪Winters pass, springs come; bound for lifetimes, fate ties me to you♪
♪봄이 오고 생사 함께할 운명은 너에게 달렸네♪
♪Mountains, rivers, lakes and seas, I follow no one but you♪
♪산과 바다를 가리지 않고 너만 따라가리♪
♪Perhaps endless tangling is our silent bond♪
♪아마도 꼬이고 얽히는 것도 궁합인지♪
♪Love and feud balance out, I'm yours alone♪
♪사랑과 원한을 상쇄하고 너를 마음에 새기네♪
♪Fated foes, fate plays tricks; you complete my five elements♪
♪숙명의 적인데 하늘이 맺어 오행에는 너만 빠졌네♪
♪Burning love, unbridled hatred, they suit each other well♪
♪사랑은 뜨겁고 미움은 시원하니 서로 어울리네♪
♪If you don't leave, I'll never abandon you♪
♪네가 떠나지 않는다면 나 또한 포기하지 않으리♪
♪We'll dwell in mortal dust, stay side by side till the end♪
♪이렇게 속세에서 끝까지 함께하리♪